CHARLES JACKSON

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER



ABOUT

I can't count the number of times I've been using an application and thought to myself, "Why can't they just create an easier and/or more efficient way to do the task at hand?" However, what good are my ideas if I can't do anything about them? The alarming frequency of these occurrences, along with the desire to take action in creating a solution is what sparked my initial interest in software development.

I started learning code through self-study online, but found myself constantly wanting a more engaging learning environment. For this reason, it wasn't until I joined the community of curious minds at Nashville Software School, that I truly began to enjoy the challenge of learning a new technological language. I look forward to a lifetime of daily growth of in software development.

PROJECTS

HAIR GUY'D

Hair Guy'd is a single-page web application built with React JS. It is a centralized resource that fathers can use to guide (guy'd) other men on how to do their daughter's hair through pictures, written instructions, and video tutorials. A user can sign in, choose their daughter's hair texture, and then search through a list of tutorials for various styles specifically for the hair texture selected. Users also have the option to add, edit, and delete their own tutorials. This application was styled primarily with Bulma, but also employs React Bootstrap.



github.com/CPJackson777/Frontend-Capstone

EDUCATION

NASHVILLE SOFTWARE SCHOOL

Full Stack Development bootcamp

MIDDLE TENNESSEE STATE UNIVERSITY

B.S. in Communication and Media Studies

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

NASHVILLE SOFTWARE SCHOOL

FULL STACK SOFTWARE DEVELOPER | SEPTEMBER 2019 - PRESENT

- Developed dynamic single-page applications using React in addition to modern ES6+ Javascript
- Learned fundamentals such as HTML, CSS, JSON, modular code, commenting code, and reusuable components
- Gained soft skills through frequent group projects allowing many opportunities for planning, team work, ticket assignments, and problem solving
- Trained in database structure and using Entity Relationship Diagrams
- Used Github to perform and review pull requests to ensure working code free of merge conflicts
- Experience with styling using Bulma and Bootstrap

GROUP PROJECTS

NUTSHELL

- This project was done twice. The first round was a collaboration with a team of three
 using Javascript, HTML, CSS to build a social media app called Otter. The second round
 was a single-page social application created by a group of four team members using
 React JS
- For the Javascript app, I was individually responsible for the Events module where users are able to complete a form and successfully add Events to the dashboard. For the React app, I was responsible for the messages components which allow users to create, add and delete messages
- Implemented dynamic time stamping to messages directly within messages components
- Collectively designed an Entity Relationship Diagram (ERD), created wire frame, and pair coded a welcome page.
- Fetched data from JSON Server and used browser local and session storage



http://bit.ly/group-react-nutshell

BEST AMERICAN HOSPITALITY, INC

HELP DESK SUPPORT SPECIALIST | JUNE 2016 - SEPTEMBER 2019

Best American Hospitality® has headquarters in Atlanta, Georgia, and Nashville, Tennessee. It operates multi-unit Church's Chicken restaurants in the states of California, Texas and Arizona as well as Shoney's restaurants across the Southeastern United States.

- Provided remote and/or direct support for computer and POS system related issues such as network failures, employee fingerprint issues, and payroll
 audit issues
- Answered, detailed, and solved support tickets in Zendesk sent in by restaurant managers and corporate employees
- Imaged hard drives for restaurant offices and registers based on their specific application needs, computer make/model, and operating system
- Installed office printers, thermal receipt printers, touch-screen monitors, fingerprint readers, and credit card readers both on site as well as remotely
- Edited, replaced, and/or maintained various files to ensure proper functioning of office and restaurant equipment for over 50 restaurant locations
- Created and edited knowledge base articles in Zendesk for departmental use

CGS ADMINISTRATORS, LLC

MEDICARE APPEALS ASSOCIATE | DECEMBER 2011 - JUNE 2016

CGS Administrators, LLC is a leading provider of administrative and business services for healthcare programs and stakeholders, including Medicare beneficiaries, providers, and medical equipment suppliers.

- Reviewed incoming appeals to determine medical justification for durable medical equipment provided to Medicare beneficiaries
- Chosen to participate in the Durable Medical Equipment Appeals Lean Team. Our team critically analyzed the appeals process/systems and made
 effective revisions resulting in a more streamlined process which increased overall departmental production
- Achieved 100% quality audit scores multiple months and regularly met or exceeded the 93% accuracy metric

PROVIDER ENROLLMENT SENIOR ASSOCIATE | AUGUST 2010 - DECEMBER 2011

- Reviewed provider enrollment applications to ensure that all required information was completed and processed applications for enrollment after requirements were met
- Ensured provider integrity and that suppliers are in compliance with established Medicare standards and guidelines
- Drafted development, denial, and/or approval letters based on the results of my credentialing
- Elected to assist with training new hires on the credentialing process in addition to training current employees who are expanding their skill sets within
 the provider enrollment department

CUSTOMER SERVICE REPRESENTATIVE | MAY 2008 - AUGUST 2010

- Answered incoming calls from durable medical equipment providers and provided quality service in a timely manner in order to accurately assist them
 with their issues
- Served as a mentor for new hires to provide support, direction, and assist in acclimation to their new role
- Chosen by management to write an article which was published in the November 2009 edition of Medicare Matters
- March of Dimes Representative for the DME Customer Service Department and helped raise over \$61,000 from 2008 to 2009